

# SIDDHARTH GARG

Developer, Al Engineer, CFA - Passed level 1

- @ i@siddharthgarg.in
- ▼ India | Remote (Preferred)
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sidg510/

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelors in Technology, Computer Science | VIT Vellore (Institute of Eminence)

- **\*\*** 07/2018 06/2022
- Vellore, India
- CGPA: 9.07

12th Grade, All India Senior School Certificate Examination(AISSCE) | Delhi Public School, RK Puram

- **\*\*** 07 2015 05 2017
- New Delhi, India
- Score: 90%

10th Grade, All India Secondary School Certificate (AISSC) | Delhi Public School, Agra

- **2015**
- New Delhi, India
- CGPA: 9.4

## **TECH STACK**

#### **Programming**

Python  $\int SQL \int JavaScript C++ \int C \int Java$ 

#### AI/ML

Data Science | Image Recognition | CNNs

Sentiment Analysis RNNs Object Detection

#### **Full Stack Development**

NodeJS ReactJS React Native SQL

MongoDB

## UI/UX

Figma Illustrator Canva Photoshop

## **CERTIFICATIONS**



Cleared Level 1 of Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) Examination

TensorFlow Developer Certificate
Google's Official TensorFlow Developer Certificate

IBM AI Engineering

IBM AI Engineering Professional Certification

Consecutive First Prize, RCPC 2020 and 2019 Coding Competition, involving severalrounds by ACM, VIT

Skydiving

Tandem Skydiving Certificate, Pattaya

# **ABOUT ME**

Started learning to write code when I was 12 years old, there was no going back from there. I enjoy my work, let it be Tech, Design or Finance, I love exploring different disciplines and developing solutions, that create value. Love to travel, been to (almost) everywhere in the country.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Member Tech | DE Shaw India

**i** Jan 2022 – 5 Mar 2024

Hyderabad, India

Acquired in-depth Finance and Technical knowledge in Fundamental equities team. Developed and maintained ETL pipelines for multiple alternative data sources, which were used to generate trading signals in both systematic and discretionary models. Also developed a data validation framework from scratch to reduce noise from the generated signal, additionally reducing time from 1hr to 12mins.

#### Intern Member Tech | DE Shaw India

**May 2021 - July 2021** 

Remote (Hyderabad Office)

Developed an extendible python application for tracking different internal tools' performance. Worked with Elastic, Logstash, Influx and Kibana.

#### Computer Vision Engineer | FindMind Analytics

iii Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

Programmed a high accuracy end to end pipeline with a REST API for OCR and masking of clients' sensitive documents using object detection, increasing speed 30x and accuracy to 97% from 60%

Marketing Head, Vellore Executive Board & Volunteer | ERIDE (NGO)

**Sep 2018 - Dec 2020** 

Vellore India

Empowering Rural India with Digital Education(ERIDE) aims on delivering digital literacy tounderprivileged people. Joined as a freshman, from teaching kids in orphanages, community centres to leading the NGO as a board member

Creative Head | Mozilla Firefox Club VIT

**Sep 2019 - Dec 2020** 

Vellore, India

Oversaw the club's activities, mentored designers, guided junior members in technical projects.

Senior Core Committee Member, Tech | Computer Society of India, VIT

Dec 2018 - Dec 2019

Vellore, India

Organized hackathons, lead workshops and programmed CTFs, with amazingly talented people I was fortunate enough to work with them on projects exposing students to new concepts.

#### **PROJECTS**

Malware Family classification using Convolutional Neural Networks on Byte Sequences |

GUI based End to End Auto ML dashboard for object detection and masking. | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

REST API for OCR and masking of sensitive data in Identity documents using image processing and object detection | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

Sentiment Analysis and Topic Modelling of primetime News-hourDebates from different news channels | •

TB Saathi (Tuberculosis Diagnosis using neural networks tool) | # | 2nd Prize in Hello World Hack